but before we go to rate let's see if we
understood what codes especially parity
can do for us
suppose we are using parity to detect
bid flip errors in our DRAM memory our
unprotected memory has eight one beta
rays each of which is 1024 by 1024 bits
so we have eight small arrays each of
the arrays is given the same row and
column address and each of the arrays
outputs one bit of the overall 8-bit
value that we are trying to read or
write in this memory we want to use
parity to detect bit flips and what we
can afford is a parity bit for every
group of four data bits the question for
you is whether we should add two more
one bit arrays of this kind for parity
so the idea is that we would add another
array here and the bit stored here would
be the parity for the first four bits
here and another one would store the
parity for these four data bits or
should we add these additional parity
bits to every row in each array so that
we don't need the extra modules but what
we do is we extend each of these modules
with the extra bits that protect the
data in that row note that the overall
number of bits we add is the same in
these two approaches the question for
you is which one is better